DENIL KURIAN

PYTHON DEVELOPER/WEB DEVELOPER





Thekkemattappallil (H) Vakkad(PO) Kottayam 686636

in linkedin.com/in/denil-kurian

github.com/denilkurian

EDUCATION

Bachelor of technology (2018-2022)

APJ Abdul Kalam Technological University

Mechanical Engineering

CGPA: 7.5

Higher secondary Education (2016-2018)

Kerala Board Of Higher SecondaryEducation

Stream: Bio math

89%

Secondary Education (2016)Kerala Board Of Public Examination

90%

SKILLS

- Python, Django
- FastAPI
- HTML.CSS
- Bootstrap
- Mysql, SQlite
- Object Relational Mapping
- Javascript
- React
- Github
- Postman Api

• IDE's: VS Code, PyCharm

Os: Windows, Linux (ubuntu)

PROFILE

Motivated Python-Django developer with a solid foundation in building scalable and efficient web applications. Completed a 6-month intensive training program focused on Django development and gained 1 year of professional experience as a Junior Django Developer

WORK EXPERIENCE

DataPMI Inc- Junior Developer

August 2023 - Present

- Developing a Recruitmet management system application.
- Technologies Used: Python, Django, MySQL, HTML/CSS, React, JavaScript.

Luminar Technolab- Python Full Stack Developer(Intern)

October 2022 - April 2023

- Website creation
- Building Api's
- Build Realtime web application

PROJECTS

Recruitment Management System

- Efficiently store and manage resumes and candidate profiles from Naukri and internal sources
- Automate the assignment of daily candidate targets for recruiters, promoting fair workload distribution and streamlined workflows
- Provide a centralized platform to schedule interviews and manage interview statuses, fostering smoother candidate interaction

Chat Application

- Django channels and websockets
- Frontend-HTML,CSS,Bootstrap

CERTIFICATIONS

Python Web Development Expert - National Council for Technology and Training

LANGUAGES

- English
- Malayalam